George Dewey Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
George Dewey Papers 1805-1949 1885-1931
MSS18366
Dewey, George, 1837-1917
25,000 items
86 containers plus 6 oversize
42.8 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Naval officer. Correspondence, letterbooks, diaries, journal, military papers, financial papers, scrapbooks, and photographs chiefly relating to Dewey's activities as naval commander in the Far East during the Spanish-American War, especially at the battle of Manila Bay; as admiral and president of the General Board of the Navy; president of the court of inquiry concerning Winfield Scott Schley; and commander-in-chief of naval winter maneuvers.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bonaparte, Charles J. (Charles Joseph), 1851-1921--Correspondence.; Bugher, Frederick M. (Frederick McLean)--Correspondence.; Chandler, William E. (William Eaton), 1835-1917--Correspondence.; Cortelyou, George B. (George Bruce), 1862-1940--Correspondence.; Creel, George, 1876-1953--Correspondence.; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948--Correspondence.; Dewey family--Correspondence.; Dewey, George G. (George Goodwin), -1963--Correspondence.; Dewey, George, 1837-1917.; Dewey, Julius Y. (Julius Yemans)--Correspondence.; Dewey, Mary Perrin, -1843?--Correspondence.; Dewey, Mildred McLean Hazen, 1850-1931. Mildred McLean Hazen Dewey papers.; Dodge, Grenville M., 1831-1916--Correspondence.; Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881--Correspondence.; Hay, John, 1838-1905--Correspondence.; Hazen, William Babcock, 1830-1887--Correspondence.; Lansing, Robert, 1864-1928--Correspondence.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924--Correspondence.; Long, John Davis, 1838-1915--Correspondence.; Mahan, A. T. (Alfred Thayer), 1840-1914--Correspondence.; McLean, John R. (John Roll), 1848-1916--Correspondence.; Moody, William H. (William Henry), 1853-1917--Correspondence.; Morton, Paul, 1857-1911--Correspondence.; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945--Correspondence.; Poe, Elisabeth Ellicott, 1886-1947--Correspondence.; Proctor, Redfield, 1831-1908--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919--Correspondence.; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937--Correspondence.; Sargent, Nathan, 1849-1907.; Schley, Winfield Scott, 1839-1911.; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891--Correspondence.; Untermyer, Alvin, 1882-1963--Correspondence.; Williams, Oscar Fitzalan, 1843-1909--Correspondence.
Organizations
Mayflower (Yacht); Olympia (Cruiser); Pensacola (Screw steamer); Rosiclare Lead and Fluorspar Mining Company.; United States. Navy--History--Spanish-American War, 1898.; United States. Navy--Maneuvers.; United States. Navy. Asiatic Squadron.; United States. Navy. European Station.; United States. Navy. General Board.
Subjects
Courts-martial and courts of inquiry--United States.; Manila Bay, Battle of, Philippines, 1898.; Spanish-American War, 1898--Campaigns.
Occupations
Naval officers.
Acquistion Information
The papers of George Dewey, naval officer, were deposited in the Library of Congress by his son, George G. Dewey, from 1933 to 1937 and were converted to a gift in 1952. Additional material was given to the Library in 1940 by J. O. Thorn and in 1963 by the estate of George G. Dewey. Further additions were transferred to the Library by the National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution, in 1990 and 1992.
Related Material
The Manuscript Division also holds a separate collection of George Dewey papers as part of its Naval Historical Foundation Collection.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Maps and atlases have been transferred to the Geography and Map Division, where a finding aid to this material is available at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.gmd/eadgmd.gm017003. Photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the George Dewey Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of George Dewey are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1837, Dec. 26 Born, Montpelier, Vt.
1854 M.M.S., Norwich University, Northfield, Vt.
1858 Graduated, U.S. Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md.
1858 1861 Attached to steam frigate Wabash
1861 Promoted to lieutenant, U.S. Navy Assigned as executive officer on the steam sloop-of-war Mississippi
1861 1865 Took part in Civil War naval engagements at Fort St. Phillip and Fort Jackson, 1862; Port Hudson, 1862; New Orleans, 1862; Donaldsonville, 1863; and Fort Fisher, 1864-1865; also served with the North Atlantic Blockading Squadron and on the Mississippi, Monogahela, Brooklyn, Minnesota, Colorado, and Agawam
1865 Promoted to lieutenant commander
1865 1867 Served on the Kearsarge and the Canandaigua and commanded the steam frigate Colorado
1867 Married Susie Goodwin (died 1872)
1867 1869 Assigned to the U.S. Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md.
1870 1875 Commanded the sloop Narragansett
1872 Promoted to commander
1875 1882 Assigned to the Lighthouse Board
1882 1884 Commanded the steam sloop Juaniata of the Asiatic Squadron
1884 Promoted to captain
1885 1888 Commanded the screw steamer Pensacola, flagship of the European Squadron
1889 1896 Chief, Navy Department's Bureau of Equipment, and served on the Lighthouse Board
1895 1897 President, Board of Inspection and Survey, U.S. Navy
1896 Promoted to commodore
1898 1899 Commanded Asiatic Squadron from flagship Olympia
1898, May 1 Battle of Manila Bay
1898, May 7 Promoted to rear admiral
1898, Aug. 18 Assisted Major-General Wesley Merritt, U.S. Army, in the capture of Manila, Philippines
1899 Promoted to admiral Married Mildred McLean Hazen
1900 1917 President, General Board of the Navy
1901 President, Schley Court of Inquiry
1902 1903 Commander-in-chief, combined U.S. naval force assembled at Culebra, Puerto Rico, for winter maneuvers
1917, Jan. 16 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of George Dewey (1837-1917) span the years 1805-1949, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1885-1931. The collection primarily concerns Dewey's naval career after 1885 and consists of diaries, correspondence, letterbooks, military papers, clippings, printed matter, financial records, scrapbooks, and memorial volumes comprising the following series: Diaries, General Correspondence, Military File, Financial File, Miscellany, Addition, and Oversize.
The General Correspondence and Military File include correspondence and letterbooks focusing on Dewey's service as a naval commander in the Far East during the Spanish-American War commanding the Asiatic Squadron of the United States Navy, specifically his command of the cruiser Olympia at the Battle of Manila Bay, 1 May 1898, and the subsequent capture of Manila in August 1898. Of special interest are the correspondence and letterbooks for the period 1898-1899, particularly correspondence from Oscar Fitzalan Williams, American consul in Manila. The Military File contains copies of telegrams between Dewey and John Davis Long, secretary of the navy; Theodore Roosevelt, assistant secretary of the navy; Oscar Fitzalan Williams; and the American consuls in Shanghai, Tokyo, and Hong Kong. The material also relates to Dewey's service as commander of the screw steamer Pensacola, flagship of the European Squadron, 1885-1888; admiral of the navy and president of the General Board of the Navy, 1899-1917; president of the Winfield Scott Schley court of inquiry, 1901; and commander-in-chief of naval maneuvers while aboard the presidential yacht Mayflower, 1902-1903.
The General Correspondence series also includes letters exchanged between Dewey's parents, Mary Perrin and Julius Y. Dewey, and other family members. Letters from William T. Sherman and James A. Garfield in 1874 to Mildred Dewey's first husband, William B. Hazen, are also in the General Correspondence. Other prominent correspondents include Charles J. Bonaparte, William E. Chandler, George B. Cortelyou, George Creel, Josephus Daniels, Grenville Mellen Dodge, John Hay, Robert Lansing, John Davis Long, A. T. Mahan, William H. Moody, Paul Morton, Truman Handy Newberry, Redfield Proctor, Theodore Roosevelt (1858-1919), Elihu Root, and Oscar Fitzalan Williams. An index to most of the letters is filed at the beginning of the series.
The Financial File includes correspondence and records that reveal Dewey's large real estate holdings and other investments. Among the Miscellany series are clippings, genealogical and biographical material, memorabilia, memorial volumes, notes, printed matter, records of the Naval Order of the United States, and scrapbooks. Also, there is a typescript of an article written in 1904 by Commander Nathan Sargent entitled "Admiral Dewey and the Manila Campaign," an account of the Battle of Manila Bay and subsequent actions and operations of Dewey and the Asiatic Squadron.
The Addition includes general correspondence and material pertaining chiefly to the estate of Dewey's second wife, Mildred McLean Hazen Dewey. Correspondence includes Dewey's letters to Mildred Dewey and letters he received from others, many of which relate to his service as president of the Schley court of inquiry and Mildred Dewey's exchanges with Frederick M. Bugher, Josephus Daniels, her stepson George G. Dewey, Henry Cabot Lodge (1850-1924), her brother John R. McLean, Elisabeth Ellicott Poe, and Alvin Untermyer. A daughter of the founder of the Washington Post, Mildred Dewey held a sizable estate at her death. The estate file documents the disposition of the estate and includes correspondence of family members and lawyers, including Democratic Party presidential contender John W. Davis (1873-1955). Family interests in the Rosiclare Lead and Fluorspar Mining Co., which was owned by Mildred Dewey's father, Washington McLean, is documented in the estate file as well as the financial file.
Miscellaneous files among the additional material include clippings, a copy of a letter by Thomas Jefferson to Katharine Duane Morgan, memorabilia, notes, poetry, printed matter, and a report on the reception of Dewey at Washington, D.C., October 2-3 1899. Commissions, citations, degrees, awards, posters, and memorial volumes comprise the Oversize series.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Diaries, 1882-1909
General Correspondence, 1820-1919
Military File, 1876-1916
Financial File, 1883-1916
Miscellany, 1805-1923
Addition, 1811-1949
Oversize, 1872-1917
Container List
- Diaries, 1882-1909 (Box 1-2)
  Diaries of George and Mildred McLean Hazen Dewey.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Dewey, George (Box 1)
    - 1882-1895, (6 folders)
    - 1896-1909, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Dewey, Mildred McLean Hazen, 1900-1907
    - Set I, (4 folders)
    - Set II, (3 folders)
- General Correspondence, 1820-1919 (Box 3-43)
  Primarily letters received with copies of some letters sent.
  Arranged chronologically. Includes an index to most of the correspondence.
  - Index, 1898-1917, (3 vols.) (Box 3)
  - 7 Apr. 1820-4 May 1898, (10 folders) (Box 4)
  - 5-31 May 1898, (8 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1 June-6 Sept. 1898, (7 folders) (Box 6)
  - 9 Sept. 1898-28 Feb. 1899, (10 folders) (Box 7)
  - 2 Mar.-30 June 1899, (7 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1 July-30 Sept. 1899, (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - 2 Oct. 1899-28 Feb. 1900, (7 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1 Mar.-30 Oct. 1900, (9 folders) (Box 11)
  - 3 Nov. 1900-27 Feb. 1902, (8 folders) (Box 12)
  - 10 Mar. 1902-28 Feb. 1903, (7 folders) (Box 13)
  - 10 Mar.-27 June 1903, (6 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1 July-31 Dec. 1903, (7 folders) (Box 15)
  - 4 Jan.-30 June 1904, (7 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1 July 1904-17 Jan. 1905, (7 folders) (Box 17)
  - 18 Jan.-31 May 1905, (8 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1 June-23 Dec. 1905, (7 folders) (Box 19)
  - 24 Dec. 1905-17 May 1906, (7 folders) (Box 20)
  - 19 May-31 Dec. 1906, (7 folders) (Box 21)
  - 2 Jan.-29 June 1907, (6 folders) (Box 22)
  - 1 July 1907-17 Feb. 1908, (8 folders) (Box 23)
  - 18 Feb.-29 June 1908, (8 folders) (Box 24)
  - 6 July 1908-26 Feb. 1909, (8 folders) (Box 25)
  - 1 Mar.-20 Dec. 1909, (8 folders) (Box 26)
  - 21 Dec. 1909-31 May 1910, (10 folders) (Box 27)
  - 3 June-31 Dec. 1910, (9 folders) (Box 28)
  - 1 Jan.-30 Apr. 1911, (8 folders) (Box 29)
  - 1 May-18 Dec. 1911, (8 folders) (Box 30)
  - 19 Dec. 1911-20 Apr. 1912, (9 folders) (Box 31)
  - 22 Apr.-21 Oct. 1912, (10 folders) (Box 32)
  - 23 Oct. 1912-7 Jan. 1913, (8 folders) (Box 33)
  - 8 Jan.-30 Apr. 1913, (8 folders) (Box 34)
  - 1 May-16 Oct. 1913, (6 folders) (Box 35)
  - 17 Oct. 1913-31 Jan. 1914, (8 folders) (Box 36)
  - 1 Feb.-6 May 1914, (7 folders) (Box 37)
  - 6 May-24 Dec. 1914, (9 folders) (Box 38)
  - 25 Dec. 1914-13 May 1915, (9 folders) (Box 39)
  - 14 May-31 Dec. 1915, (8 folders) (Box 40)
  - 2 Jan.-9 May 1916, (8 folders) (Box 41)
  - 10 May-30 Dec. 1916, (9 folders) (Box 42)
  - 2 Jan. 1917-29 May 1919, undated, (6 folders) (Box 43)
- Military File, 1876-1916 (Box 43-53)
  Letterbooks, ships' records, reports, telegrams, printed matter, and miscellany.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material and chronologically thereunder.
  - General Board of the Navy, 1900-1902, undated, (2 folders) (Box 43)
  - Miscellany, 1897-1907, undated, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Mayflower (yacht)
    - Journal, 1902-03
    - Letterbooks
      - 8 Dec. 1902-6 Jan. 1903
      - 5-15 Jan. 1903, undated (Box 45)
  - Olympia (cruiser)
    - Forwarding books, 1897-1899, (3 vols.)
    - Letterbooks (Box 46)
      - Flag secretary, 1898-1899, (2 vols.)
      - Navy Department letters, 1898-99, (2 vols.)
      - Station letters (Box 47)
        - 14 Sept. 1897-23 Dec. 1898, (3 vols.)
        - 15 Oct. 1898-29 Sept. 1899, (3 vols.) (Box 48)
    - Supplies and maintenance records, 1897-1899, (3 folders) (Box 49)
  - Pensacola (screw steamer), letterbooks
    - Received, 1885-1888
    - Sent, 1885-1888, (2 vols.) (Box 50)
  - Printed matter, 1897-1904, undated
  - Registers of salutes and official visits, 1891-1899, (2 vols.)
  - Reports and background material, 1876-1916, undated, (3 folders) (Box 51)
  - Spanish documents found at Cavite, Philippines, 1898, (2 folders)
  - Telegrams (Box 52)
    - Originals
      - 26 Feb. 1898-30 Apr. 1899, (9 folders)
      - 1 May-31 Aug. 1899, (2 folders) (Box 53)
    - Transcripts, 1895-1899, (5 folders)
- Financial File, 1883-1916 (Box 54-62)
  Account books, correspondence, receipts, and material related to real estate, loans, and investments.
  - Account books, 1899-1901, 1914-1916 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence
    - Index, 1900-1916
    - Feb. 1900-Apr. 1901, (3 folders)
    - May 1901-Aug. 1902, (6 folders) (Box 55)
    - Sept. 1902-Aug. 1904, (6 folders) (Box 56)
    - Sept. 1904-July 1906, (6 folders) (Box 57)
    - Aug. 1906-Feb. 1910, (6 folders) (Box 58)
    - Mar. 1910-Apr. 1914, (6 folders) (Box 59)
    - May 1914-Apr. 1916, undated, (4 folders) (Box 60)
  - Investments and loans, circa 1900-circa 1913
  - Real estate and loans, 1885-1916, (8 folders) (Box 61)
  - Real estate and loans, 1885-1916, (5 folders) (Box 62)
  - Receipts, 1883-1916, undated, (2 folders)
  - Taxes, 1913-1914, undated
- Miscellany, 1805-1923 (Box 63-72)
  Appointment books, articles re Dewey, certificates, clippings, genealogical and biographical material, memorial volumes, letterbooks, memorabilia, record books, notes, poetry, printed matter, and scrapbooks.
  - Appointment books, 1901-1912, (2 vols.) (Box 63)
  - Articles
    - "Admiral Dewey and the Manila Campaign," by Nathan Sargent, 1904
    - "The Attack of the Federal Fleet, under the Command of Admiral Farragut, upon the Confederate Batteries at Port Hudson, La., and the Destruction of the Mississippi commanded by Lieut. Com. George Dewey," by H. C. Haskins, undated
  - Citations, degrees, and awards, 1892-1917 See also Oversize
  - Clippings, 1805-1910, undated, (11 folders) (Box 64)
  - Genealogical and biographical material, undated
  - Greeting cards, 1911-1916, undated
  - Invitations, 1899-1913, undated, (4 folders) (Box 65)
  - Memorabilia, 1883-1916, undated, (3 folders); (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 66, Box 67)
  - Memorial volumes
    - Dewey Home Fund, 1899, (1 vol.); (2 vols.) (Box 68)
    - Dewey Watch Fund, 1899 See Oversize (Box 69)
    - New York, N.Y., 1899 See Oversize
    - Philadelphia, Pa., 1899 See Oversize
    - Shipping interests of New York, 1898-1899 See Oversize
  - Naval Order of the United States
    - General Commandery
      - General recorder, letterbooks, 1899-1904, (3 vols.)
      - Triennial Congress, Boston, Mass., 1895
    - New York Commandery, record books, 1894-1923, (3 vols.) (Box 70)
  - Notes and fragmentary material, 1893-1911, undated
  - Poetry and music, 1897-1913, undated
  - Printed matter, 1874-1917, undated, (6 folders) (Box 71)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 72)
    - Vol. I, 1899, (2 folders)
    - Vol. II, 1901-1907, (4 folders)
    - Vol. III, 1907-1916, (4 folders)
  - Speech, undated
- Addition, 1811-1949 (Box 73-86)
  - General Correspondence 1896-1931 (Box 73-76)
    Letters sent and received.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically thereunder.
    - Dewey, George (Box 73)
      - Dewey, Mildred McLean Hazen (wife), 1896-1906, (10 folders)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1850-1924), 1898 See also Container 74, same heading
      - Others
        - 1898-1901, (2 folders)
        - 1902-1915, undated, (3 folders) (Box 74)
      - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1906-1908 See also Container 76, same heading
    - Dewey, Mildred McLean Hazen
      - Bugher, Frederick H. (nephew), 1904-1923
      - Bugher, Frederick McLean (grandnephew), 1919-1930, undated
      - Daniels, Josephus, 1923-1924, undated
      - Dewey, George Goodwin (stepson), 1906-1930, undated, (3 folders)
      - Dewey Congressional Medal Men's Association, 1927-1931
      - Longworth, Alice Roosevelt See Container 76, Roosevelt, Alice Lee
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1850-1924), 1923 See also Container 73, same heading
      - McCully, N. A., 1926-1927
      - McLean, John R. (brother), 1904, 1914-1915
      - Navy League of the United States, Women's Section, 1915-1923, undated
      - Others, 1899-1931, undated, (7 folders) (Box 75)
      - Poe, Elisabeth Ellicott, 1915-1923, undated, (3 folders)
      - Roosevelt, Alice Lee, undated (Box 76)
      - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1904 See also Container 74, same heading
      - Thissal, H. D., 1916, undated
      - Untermyer, Alvin, 1923-1930, undated, (2 folders)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, 1917
  - Estate File, 1811-1949 (Box 76-80)
    Correspondence, account statements, clippings, deeds, and legal documents.
    - Adirondack, N.Y., property (Box 76)
      - Bell, Frank L., 1927-1935, undated
      - Benedict, Farrand N., 1934-1935
      - Chittenden, Henry T., 1927-1928
      - Davis, John W. (1873-1955), 1928-1934, undated
      - Deeds and legal papers, 1811-1928, undated
      - Harrison, Walter J., 1927-1934
      - Snyder, David E., 1934-1935
      - Untermyer, Alvin, 1927-1928
    - Audubon, John James, drawings by, 1931-1933
    - Bills against Dewey estate, 1933
    - Bugher, Frederick McLean
      - Bid for estate, 1947
      - Distribution received, 1926-1934, undated
      - Expenses, 1930-1933
    - Burial, 1925-1933 (Box 77)
    - Business Economic Digest, 1931-1934
    - Clippings, 1928-1933, undated
    - Dewey, George Goodwin
      - Correspondence, 1924, undated
      - Settlement with, 1932-1934
      - Trophies and relics, 1932
    - Estate sale, 1933-1934
    - General correspondence, 1926-1936, undated
    - Hartson, Nelson T., 1933-1943
    - Mausoleum, 1933
    - Miscellany, 1928-1934, undated
    - McLean, Mary L., trusts
      - No. I, 1916-1931, undated
      - No. II, 1930-1931
    - Mortician, 1931-1933
    - National Mortgage and Investment Corp., 1934-1940, undated
    - National Savings and Trust Co. (Box 78)
      - Account statements
        - Set I, 1929-1931
        - Set II, 1932-1943, undated, (3 folders)
        - Set III, 1934-1941
      - Agreement with Mildred McLean Hazen Dewey, 1926
      - Bornet, David, 1931-1935, undated
      - Bugher, Frederick McLean, 1935-1936
      - General correspondence, 1933-1949, (4 folders) (Box 79)
      - Miscellany, 1924-1945, undated
      - Review of Dewey trust, 1935-1940
    - Ogilby, C. F. R., 1930-1936, undated
    - Personal property, 1925-1926, undated (Box 80)
    - Photography, 1927-1933
    - Real estate outside Washington, D.C., 1933-1934
    - Rosiclare Lead and Fluorspar Mining Co., 1916-1934, (2 folders)
    - Security Storage Co., 1927-1939
    - Servants, 1931-1933
    - Untermyer, Alvin, 1924-1934, (3 folders)
    - Untermyer, Eugene and Samuel, 1925-1934
    - Weissberger, Arnold, re statements of witnesses, 1931-1934, (2 folders)
    - Wills, 1925, 1931
  - Financial File, 1912-1932 (Box 81-85)
    Correspondence, account statements, and account books.
    - Account books, 1916-1924 (Box 81)
    - American Security and Trust Co., 1916-1930, (2 folders)
    - General correspondence, 1916-1932, undated, (3 folders)
    - Income taxes, 1913-1929
    - Miscellany, 1912-1926, undated (Box 82)
    - National City Bank of New York, 1923-1929, (2 folders)
    - National Savings and Trust Co.
      - Account statements
        - 1922-1929, (4 folders)
        - 1930 (Box 83)
      - Authorization for payments, 1926-1931, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1917-1930
    - Riggs National Bank
      - Account statements, 1922-1925
      - Correspondence
        - Nov. 1920-May 1923
        - June 1923-Jan. 1926, (3 folders) (Box 84)
    - Rosiclare Lead and Fluorspar Mining Co.
      - June 1921-July 1928, (3 folders)
      - Aug. 1928-Aug. 1930, (2 folders) (Box 85)
  - Miscellany, 1817-1929 (Box 85-86)
    Certificates, clippings, commissions, copy of a Thomas Jefferson letter, memorabilia, notes, poetry, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material or topic and chronologically thereunder.
    - Calling cards, undated (Box 85)
    - Certificates, 1905-1909
    - Clippings, 1901-1934, undated, (2 folders)
    - Commissions, 1872-1899 See Oversize
    - Extracts from Mildred Dewey's diary, 1900-1901
    - Invitations, 1926-1929, undated, (2 folders)
    - Jefferson, Thomas, copy of letter to Katharine Duane Morgan, 26 Jan. 1822
    - Memorabilia, 1898-1925, undated, (2 folders)
    - Memorials, 1917 (Box 86)
    - Notes, undated
    - Passport signed by John Quincy Adams, secretary of state, copy, 1817
    - Poetry and music, 1897-1923, undated
    - Posters, undated See Oversize
    - Printed matter, 1909, 1923
    - Reception of Admiral George Dewey, U.S.N., at Washington, Oct. 2 and 3, 1899, report of the Admiral Dewey Reception Committee, 1901
    - Schley, Winfield Scott, clippings, 1901
- Oversize, 1872-1917 (Box OV 1-OV 6)
  Oversize material consisting primarily of commissions, citations, degrees, awards, memorial volumes, and posters.
  Organized and described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Citations, degrees, and awards, 1892-1917 (Container 63)
    - Memorial volumes (Box OV 2)
      - Dewey Watch Fund, 1899 (Container 69)
      - New York, N.Y., 1899 (Container 70) (Box OV 3)
      - Philadelphia, Pa., 1899 (Container 70) (Box OV 4)
      - Shipping interests of New York, 1898-1899 (Container 70) (Box OV 5)
  - Addition (Box OV 6)
    - Miscellany
      - Commissions, 1872-1899 (Container 86)
      - Posters, undated (Container 87)